KENRICK TAM

APPLYING FOR WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

E: kenricktam@gmail.com

G: github.com/KnrkTam [GitHub]

P: (437) 973-8229

L: Kenrick Tam [Link]

PERSONAL PROFILE

Programmer with industrial experiences building web application and CMS system. specialised in JavaScript & TypeScript and have professional experience working with PHP and Codelgniter. I also have experience working with ReactJs, NextJs, and Google Firebase.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language

- Typescript
- Javascript
- Python
- PHP

Frontend

- React js
- Next.js
- Material UI
- CSS, SCSS
- JQuery

Backend

- PostgreSQL
- Express.js
- Node.js
- Knex (Migration)
- MySQL
- Codeigniter
- Google firebase

DevOps

- AWS (EC2, S3, Route 53, Certificate Manager)
- Nginx

Others

- Git
- Restful API

AVAILABILITY

Immediately Available

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

PROGRAMMER - ONE SOLUTION LIMITED

Jun 2021 to Jun 2022 (1 year)

- Built and maintained 3 web applications and CMS systems from scratch independently
- · Maintained, updated and troubleshot for existing projects
- Attended business meeting to report and review project status
- · Skills: PHP, Codelgniter, MySQL, MVC model

CONSULTANT (WEB DEVELOPER) - JDT CONSULTING LTD

Dec 2020 to Jun 2021 (6 months)

- Constructed and designed the database structure and webpage layout
- · Report directly to project manager on weekly basis
- 6 months contract-based full-stack programmer
- · Skills: JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT - RECRUITFIRST LIMITED

Aug 2019 to Jul 2020

 Recruited, Negotiated and Delivered between our clients and candidates from TMT sector

PERSONAL PROJECT EXPERIENCE

NEXT-FIRE - DEMO PROJECT OF REACT, NEXT.JS & FIREBASE

Demo project | Jul 2022. [link]

- Demo project with ReactJS, Next.js & Google Firebase
- Deployed with Vercel and database on Firestore

HCMLYSL - CMS system for SEN school

MVC designed system with | Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

- Developed with Javascript & PHP (Codelgniter framework)
- The end-product supports user-login (RBAC), keyword search (Serverside rendered), file upload, report generation (XIs, csv and pdf) and recursive CRUD features

ZPACE - SMALL WORKSPACE SHARING PLATFORM

Group capstone project at Tecky Academy | Nov 2020 - Dec 2020

- SPA website developed with React.js (frontend) & Express.js (backend)
- The end-product supports user-login (OAuth), search by geolocation (GoogleMAP API), real-time chat-box (Socket.io), rating and bookmark features

EDUCATION HISTORY

TECKY ACADEMY

MicroMaster in A.I. and Programming (cohort 11), Aug to Dec 2020

- 15 weeks Full-Time immersive course with several real-world projects
- Including SPA website and A.I. employed web-based application

THE UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG

Class of 2018. Graduated with Upper second class honours

· Majored in Psychology